# Zach Schneider

Software Developer

#### Contact

#### **Address**

Parkesburg, PA, 19365

#### **Phone**

(419) 376-0273

#### E-mail

zachary.schneider85@gmail.com

#### **www**

https://zschneid85.github.io/devportfolio/

#### LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in/zach-schneider-5151aa1

#### **Skills**

# **JavaScript** Very Good Java **Excellent** Git Good HTML/CSS Excellent SQL <u>Excellent</u> WordPress Excellent PHP Very Good **JQuery** Very Good Bootstrap 4 Good

PROFILE Goal-oriented Web Developer with strong commitment to collaboration and solutions-oriented problem-solving. Committed to high standards of web design, user experience, usability and speed for multiple types of users. Successful at maintaining customer satisfaction through effective customer support.

#### **Work History**

# 2018-08 -Current

# **Software Developer**

Zip Code Solutions, Parkesburg, PA

- Developing ,optimizing and maintaining websites and applications utilizing PHP, MySQL, Javascript , and various APIs to meet the goals of 30 plus clients.
- Creating an Administrative backend so that clients can quickly update data by using databases.
- Migrating existing websites/applications to a stable,
  high-maintainable platform via AWS and WordPress.
- Analyzing requirements and designing, developing and implementing software applications for multiple websites.
- Preparing and presenting technical proposals to clients focusing on needs.

# 2019-11 -Current

#### **Lead Teacher**

Wize Computing Academy, Exton, PA

- Enhanced student learning by optimizing wide range of instructional platforms Scratch, Lego wedo 2.0.
- Keeping 15 students on-task with proactive behavior modification and positive reinforcement strategies.
- Implementing lesson plans from start to finish with a Stem focused curriculum.

# 2016-11 -2018-03

# Medicaid Billing Rep

Conifer Health Solutions, Exton, PA

- Worked on 1,200 accounts per week with great attention to detail.
- Used a wide range of Medicaid billing tools to resolve a wide range of insurance denials.
- Produced \$150,000.00 per month in company revenue.

#### **Education**

2018-03 -	Certification of Completion: Software Development
2018-05	Rutgers University - New Brunswick
	Coding Bootcamp
2004-08 -	Bachelor of Science: History
2008-05	Eastern Michigan University - Ypsilanti, MI